[
  {
    "question": "What does the term 'dystopia' mean?",
    "options": [
      "A synonym for 'post-apocalyptic'",
      "A bleak or darkly imagined future",
      "An unfavourable society to live in",
      "A society that is actively working against the protagonist's aims and desires"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "An unfavourable society to live in"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is typically the antagonist in a dystopian story?",
    "options": [
      "The protagonist",
      "The government",
      "The loss of civil liberties",
      "Surveillance"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "The government"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are some causes of untenable living conditions in a dystopian society?",
    "options": [
      "Banning of books",
      "Controlled birth rate",
      "Propaganda",
      "Indoctrination"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Controlled birth rate"
  },
  {
    "question": "What determines whether a society is perceived as a dystopia?",
    "options": [
      "Point of view",
      "Surveillance",
      "Civil liberties",
      "Reproductive freedom"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Point of view"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the paradoxical situation that can arise in a dystopia?",
    "options": [
      "The loss of A is truly felt",
      "Living in a dystopia without knowing it",
      "Society gives up A in exchange for B",
      "Utopias being depicted as dystopias"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Society gives up A in exchange for B"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are some elements of a dystopia?",
    "options": [
      "A god-like ruling figure",
      "Mass hysteria as a form of control",
      "Recreation of history",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is one purpose of dystopian fiction?",
    "options": [
      "To emphasize political or societal points",
      "To entertain readers with a bleak future",
      "To provide cautionary tales",
      "To promote mass hysteria"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To provide cautionary tales"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do the best dystopias explore?",
    "options": [
      "Deeper meanings of civilization",
      "Government propaganda",
      "Indoctrination techniques",
      "Loss of civil liberties"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Deeper meanings of civilization"
  },
  {
    "question": "What can be a form of control in a dystopian society?",
    "options": [
      "Paranoia",
      "Societal organization",
      "Centralized power",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an essential aspect of dystopian society?",
    "options": [
      "Idea of humanity",
      "Reproductive freedom",
      "Control over historical records",
      "Loss of civil liberties"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Control over historical records"
  }
]
